HBO
HBO纪录片频道
你告诉我们
Well you tell us...
10月31日 下午5点17分*
你能告诉我们吗
Will you tell us?
你觉得这是什么
What do you think it is?
-嗨 爸爸  -不错
-Hi Daddy. -That's right.
2010年 3月3日
重磅新闻
观众朋友们好 首先带来今晚麦迪逊的
Hi everybody, we start with breaking news
重磅消息
in Madison tonight,
人们在沿海的一座房子中
where a body has been found
发现了一具尸体
in a waterfront home there.
今晚警方将这起案件 定性为谋杀
Police tonight are treating it as a homicide.
新闻8号频道 率先赶到中间海滩路现场
News Channel 8 first on the scene at Middle Beach Road.
新闻8号频道记者 Sara Welch
麦迪逊*
中间海滩路
发现尸体
可信报道
今晚给我们带来 直播报道
joins us live in Madison tonight,
重磅新闻 发现尸体
麦迪逊*
Sara 现场情况怎么样
and what do you know, Sara?
麦迪逊警察和本州警方
Madison police and state police have been out
今早11点半 已经到达
at this home at 44 Middle Beach Road
中间海滩路44号现场
since about 11:30 this morning.
我们来看一下 可以看到
Let’s take a look, you can see
这条路已经被警方封锁了
the road is blocked off by police,
他们将这起案件 定性为谋杀案
they are treating this case as a homicide.
这个位置 视野很模糊
It’s hard to see 44 Middle Beach Road
很难看清 中间海滩路44号的情况
from this vantage point.
已知情况为 一名年近50岁的女性
Here’s what we do know: a woman in
在自家院子中 受到伤害
her late 40s was found injured in her yard.
她被当场宣布死亡
She was pronounced dead at the scene.
警方没有公布 受害者的姓名
Police are not releasing the victim’s name,
但是新闻8号频道得知
but News Channel 8 has learned
一位名叫Barbara Hamburg的女性 租下这座房子
that a woman named Barbara Hamburg rents the house.
我说 不 这不可能是真的
I said no, you’re not telling me, that’s not real.
但这是真的
And it was real.
Barbara Lund *Barbara的妈妈
感觉自己 遭到当头一棒
It was like being hit by a boulder.
我收到我父亲的 两条语音留言
I had two voicemails from my father,
Leu的两条 Chris的三条
two voicemails from Leu, and three from Chris,
我心想 "要么是中彩票了"
and I went, "Well, either we hit the lottery
"要么是 发生了非常坏的事"
or something awful has happened."
你的第一反应是什么
What was your first reaction?
我在路上 一直有不祥的预感
Didn’t sound right the whole way up here.
Richard Beach *Barbara的哥哥
所以事实就是
You know, essentially saying that
我的妹妹 被人谋杀了
my sister had been murdered.
呃
Um…
我记得妈妈 给我发短信
I remember my mom texted me, and
我当时 正站在航站楼
I was just, like, standing in the middle of
心想 "怎么会这样"
the terminal like, "What the fuck."
你回家之后 发生了什么
What happened when you got home?
Chris Platt
Barbara的表兄
天呐 接着就是一片昏天黑地
Oh man, like the, the chaos begins.
法医判定这是一起凶杀案
The medical examiner ruling the killing a homicide,
将死者死因 描述为
describing the cause of death as
"钝器创伤和锐器致伤"
"blunt force trauma and sharp force injury."
她的伤口 是什么样的
What kind of wounds did she have?
Conway Beach
Barbara的姐姐
她被人捅了 头部受了重伤
She was stabbed, she had a terrible head wound,
她的颈动脉被刺伤 全身都是伤
her carotid artery was stabbed… all over.
他们说她有18处伤
They say it was 18 times.
目前验尸官 法医
Right now the coroner and ME,
州警 还有麦迪逊警察
state police, along with Madison
都在现场
police are on the scene,
试图找出 谁杀了这个女人
trying to figure out who killed this woman.
警方没有说 这个案子是随机作案
Police won’t say if the killing was random,
还是有目标作案
or if this mother was targeted.
Jill Platt
Barbara的大姨
这是一场激情犯罪
This is a crime of passion.
要不是因为 私人恩怨
People don’t get murdered, and that brutally,
人们不会下此毒手
without it being a very personal thing.
Barbara Hamburg当时48岁
Stunned and shocked, friends of
她的朋友 听闻消息后极为震惊
48-year-old Barbara Hamburg
纷纷在脸书上 向她未成年的
Flooding Facebook, offering sympathy
儿子和女儿 表示同情和慰问
for her teenage son and daughter.
与此同时 警探们在搜查
Meantime, detectives combing
发现尸体的那个院子
the yard where she was found.
Ali Hamburg
Barbara的女儿
中部海滩路 西
我知道 回想往事让你很难受
I know it’s uh, it’s tough to think about this,
我有一些问题
I just have a couple questions.
没关系
Yeah, it’s fine.
你回家时 印象最深刻的是什么事
What was your best recollection of coming home?
我感觉不对劲
Something wasn’t right.
我们给她打电话 但联系不到她
We were calling her, we couldn’t get in touch with her..
Ali和我停下车 Ali说
Ali and I pulled up and Ali’s like,
"妈妈的车 为什么停在车道上"
"Why is Mom’s car in the driveway?"
我说 "我不知道"
And I said, "I don’t know.
"Ali 我不知道"
I don’t know, Al."
她的钥匙插在门上 但是门还锁着
Her keys were in the door, but the door was locked.
我们进屋之后 大喊她的名字
And we go inside, and we’re screaming her name.
我们在喊她 但不知道她在哪
We’re calling out for her, we don’t know where she is.
哪也找不到她
She’s nowhere to be found.
一切都不对劲
Nothing is making sense.
我绕着房子转 听到Conway在尖叫
I go around the house, and I hear Conway screaming.
我看到垫子 堆叠在一起
I see these cushions up against the bushes,
我心想 "怎么回事"
and I’m like, "What the hell?"
我扯开一个垫子 心想"啊"
So I pull one cushion off and I’m like, "Ah.
"底下是小动物吧"
It’s an animal."
你为什么觉得 会是小动物
Why did you think it was an animal?
我看到的 全是乱糟糟的血和毛发
All I could see was, like, mushedCup hair and blood.
你掀开第二个垫子后 看到了什么
So, you pull back the second cushion, what happens?
是你妈妈
It’s your mom.
嗨 麦迪逊
Hi, Madison.
麦迪逊 嗨
Madison! Hi!
Erin Cox
Barbara Hamburg的儿子 在脸书上发了一条动态
Barbara Hamburg’s son posted a message on Facebook,
说现在大家都要 坚强起来
saying now is the time to stay strong,
他妈妈会希望 大家能坚强
that’s what his mother would have wanted.
她说 "妈妈死了"
She said, "Mom’s dead."
我想让自己醒过来
I just wanted to wake up,
因为我知道 这一切不是真的
‘cause I knew that that couldn’t be real.
我生命中 重要的一切
Everything that was important in my life
都在顷刻之间
then within, like, a split-second...
生日快乐
Happy Birthday...
失去了一切
Meant nothing.
中间海滩上的谋杀案
第一集
妈妈死了
Jeffrey Hamburg 爸爸 Barbara Louise Beach 妈妈
Barbara Alexandra Hamburg 姐姐 Madison Chedsey Hamburg 我*
我们来简单地 游览一下康涅狄格
We’re about to take a brief tour of Connecticut.
在身处外太空的宇航员看来
In this astronaut’s eye view from outer space,
从占地面积上来看 它很渺小
it appears small,  geographically,
但越靠近它 它看起来就越大
but it looms increasingly large the closer one approaches.
康涅狄格地理位置优越
Connecticut is strategically located
位于纽约和波士顿之间
between New York and Boston,
位于东北部市场中心 经济发达
in the heart of the rich northeastern market.
这个州 经济增长势头迅猛
It’s a state of dynamic economic growth,
经济种类多样 机会繁多
rich in variety and full of opportunities.
2013年
谋杀案发生三年后
喂
Hello?
你现在忙吗
Are you busy right now?
不忙
No.
我跟你说过 我在做
So, I told you I’ve been working on,
几个项目 是吧
like, a couple projects, right?
对
Yeah.
通话中
Jeffrey Hamburg
我的爸爸
我在做有关妈妈的纪录片
I’m doing a documentary on Mom.
是吗
Oh, really?
对 我打给你是想问一下
Yeah, and I was just calling to ask you
如果你愿意的话
if you would be willing…
我这个周末 要回康涅狄格
I’m going to Connecticut this weekend,
我问你 愿不愿意
I was asking you if you would be willing to uh,
接受相关采访
to be interviewed about it.
关于什么
About what,
具体是什么
what in particular?
就是关于她的生活
Just, about, like her life.
你妈妈 是个很复杂的人
Well, your mother was a very complicated person.
有一些事 你可能
Things that youC you
见过 也可能没见过
may or may not have seen or witnessed
甚至都不知道 这些事
or were even cognizant of.
她有一部分生活
She had a life that I had no
我完全不了解 所以
idea she had, so…
你什么意思
What do you mean?
我不知道 能不能说
I’m not sure I can talk about...
我不喜欢说三道四
I certainly don’t want to say things, you
有些事我是道听途说 但也许是真的
know, that I heard secondhand, or… but may be true.
这件事情的真相 远远比我们
There’s obviously more to the story than
所了解的 更复杂
any of us really know.
他们来了
There they are.
-嗨外婆  -早上好
-Hi Grammy! -Morning.
早上好
Good morning.
Barbara Lund
我的外婆
亲爱的你好
Hi sweetness.
我的乖外孙 还好吗
How’s my dear grandson?
很好 你呢
Good, how are you?
很高兴见到你 亲爱的
It’s good to see you, honey bunch.
可以了吧 一 二 一 二
Is it good? Check one, two, one, two.
这是四位Barbara的合照
This is the, a picture of the four Barbaras.
我的妈妈 也就是太祖
That’s my mother, known as
是右边那个Barbara
Gram on the right, Barbara,
我是中间那个Barbara
and in the middle, that’s me, Barbara,
Madison的妈妈 是左边那个Barbara
and this is Madison’s mom on the left, Barbara.
小的是Ali 也就是Barbara Alexandra
And that’s Ali who is really Barbara Alexandra.
我们有四位 Barbara
So we have four Barbaras.
其中两位 已经离我们而去了
And two of them are no longer with us.
不敢相信这样的事实
It’s hard to believe that part.
这里是Madison
And we have, uh, Madison,
Ali和Brian
Ali, and Brian.
Brian是Madison的同母异父的弟弟 是名医生
Brian is Maddie’s half-brother, who’s a doctor.
对
Yeah.
真好
This is great.
我喜欢你的眼镜
I love your glasses.
我的天呐
Oh my gosh.
Barbara最像我
Barbie looked the most like me...
-对  -所有的女儿中
-Yeah. -Of all my daughters.
我去参加外婆日的时候
I would go down to Grandparent’s Day, and people
会有人过来跟我说 "我知道你是谁"
would come along and they’d say, "I know who you are."
对
Yeah.
"你是Madison的外婆"
"You’re Madison’s grandma,
"因为你和Barbara一模一样"
‘cause you look just like Barbie.
" Barbara和你一模一样"
And Barbie looks just like you."
你最后一次和她说话 是什么场景
Can you describe the last time you talked to her?
你妈妈吗
Your mom?
最后一次见她时的场景 我记得更清楚
Well, I can describe the last time I saw her better.
她就在那里 她来看我
She was here, she was visiting,
她和我坐在床上
and she and I sat in that bed,
她走之前 我们聊了很久
and talked a long time that night before
聊了生活近况 等等
she left, about life, and you know.
我清楚地记得 她离开时的样子
I remember distinctly her walking away, um…
大家笑一下
Everybody smile!
我记得 之后我和你妈妈
And I know I talked to your mom on the phone
通过很多次电话
after that, many times, but
但当时的场景 我一直忘不了
that image sticks with me.
那个场景 非常重要
That’s a- that’s a important image.
那件事之后不久
And that was not too long before
她就被谋杀了
she was murdered.
我和你妈妈 关系很好
We had a great relationship, your mom and I,
我们真的很好
we truly, truly did,
所以我非常想她
so I miss her terribly.
希望我说的这些
And hopefully this will...
会让你的作品 取得好成绩
you’ll get a good grade.
姥姥 拍这个不是为了交作业
That’s not what this is about, Grammy.
不是吗
Oh, it’s not?
不是 远不止如此
No, this is way more…
我知道了
Oh, I know.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
对我来说 最难受的就是看着你
The hardest thing for me was to watch you have to,
不得不经历这些痛苦
have to go through all
因为你当时才18岁 但你必须
that, ‘cause you were 18 and you had to
表现得像 21 22 23
act like you were 21, 22, 23,
Maddie 这一定非常难
and that had to be very, very hard, Maddie.
其他人不能代你受苦
The rest of us couldn’t do it for you,
必须一个人承受
you had to do it.
半小时前 守夜开始了
The vigil started about a half-hour ago,
家人和朋友们都凑在一起了
with family and friends gathering around.
他们点燃蜡烛 以此纪念她
They lit candles in her memory,
他们想让公众对此事记忆犹新
they want to keep it fresh in the public’s memory
好让有人站出来
in case somebody comes forward.
总是有关于你母亲谋杀案的
It’s just always that unanswered question out
悬而未决的问题冒出来
there about your mom’s murder.
这影响了整个家庭
And, um, it affects the entire family
Barbara Lund *Barbara Hamburg的妈妈
Conway Beach *Barbara Hamburg的姐姐*
我们相信 如果我们继续
We believe if we continue to
每年都举行守夜仪式 在某个地方
have these vigils every year, that somewhere,
会有某个人站出来
someone, they’ll be able to come forward
帮助警方解决这个案子
and help the police solve the case.
Conway Beach
我的大姨
Conway采访 第一条
Conway interview, take 1.
开始
Marker.
你妈妈很棒
Your mom was amazing.
她很聪明
She was so smart,
所有的男孩 都想要她
she had all the boys wanting her,
她很漂亮
she was beautiful.
有很多朋友 很多朋友
And, so many friends, so many friends.
人们就想和Barb在一起
People just wanted to be with Barb.
她是一件珍宝
She was a treasure.
她是我的宝贝妹妹
She was my baby sister.
Jill Platt
我的姨奶奶
和她在一起 很有趣
She was great fun to be around.
我还记得她上楼梯的样子
I can see her coming up the stairs.
你注意到她生活中 有什么异常的地方吗
Did you notice anything amiss or anything strange in her life?
你妈妈有秘密 我不知道
Your mother had secrets, so I don’t know,
她不会把所有秘密 告诉我
she didn’t share all her secrets with me.
但我一直都知道 她有秘密
But I always knew she had secrets that were,
这些秘密很阴暗 因为她
that were dark secrets, because she had this
喘息或者笑起来的时候
way of breathing and smiling that, um, to me,
都是为了掩盖内心
it was a cover up for something that was very
很沉重的东西
heavy in her heart.
我不知道那是什么
So, I don’t know what that was,
但我一直知道 有事发生
but I just knew there was something,
一直知道有事发生
always knew there was something.
这是你的世界 和里面重要的人
This is your world, and the important people in it.
这些人会爱你
The people who will love you,
在你长大成人的途中 会帮助你
help you, and hinder you in your job
也会阻碍你
of growing to be a man.
先说说你爸爸妈妈吧
Let’s start with your father and mother.
你出生后几天后 他们把你带回家
In a few days, they take you home,
你生命中最重要的时光开始了
and some of the most important days of your life begin.
1993年 3月14日
上午8点24分
我是只小狗
My life as a dog.
外面的天气 太吓人了
Oh, the weather outside is frightful.
嘟嘟嘟 嗖 嘟 说几句
Doo, doo-doo, sa-doo, the words.
下雪吧 下雪吧 下雪吧
Let it snow, let it snow, let it snow!
你从小含着银汤匙长大 你知道吧
Well, you grew up with a silver spoon, you know?
想要 需要的一切 你都有
You had everything you needed, wanted.
你住在漂亮的房子里
You lived in a beautiful house,
你们在康涅狄格有房子
and you had the house in Connecticut,
以前本来是 夏日度假屋
that was a summer house for a while.
啊哦 小水手
Ohh! Uh-oh! Little sailor!
说 "谢谢你 妈妈"
Say, "Thank you, Mommy."
他们想培养你
They tried to educate you.
把你送到最好的学校
Sent you to the best schools
你有保姆和司机
There were nannies and chauffeurs.
爸爸
Daddy!
真不错
Ooo! There you go!
爸爸 要去上学了 这一身真好看
Daddy! Gettin’ ready for school! That’s a nice outfit!
跟爸爸说再见
Say bye-bye to Daddy.
你爸爸是个 千万富翁
Your father was a multiCmultiCmillionaire.
他是南方电气的总裁
He was CEO of Southern Electric.
南方公司
The Southern Company.
你妈妈穿的衣服 更加高级了
You know, your mom was wearing nicer clothes
你知道
and uh, you know,
对她来说 钱不是问题
just things seemed simpler for her financially.
他看起来 人真的很不错
He seemed like a really nice man.
一开始我见你爸爸的时候 天呐
In the beginning, ah, God, the day I met your father, he…
我简直要 喜极而泣
I laughed so hard I was crying.
他是那种 最有魅力
He was one of the most charismatic,
最有趣 最聪明的人
funny, intelligent people,
对你妈妈来说 他就像
and to your mother, he was, uh,
穿着闪亮盔甲的骑士 像个王子
he was the knight in shining armor, he was a prince.
我觉得你妈妈 从内心里
I think your mom thought and believed
深深地相信
in her heart of hearts that she
她嫁给了自己的梦中情人
married the man of her dreams.
Lewis Beach
我的叔叔
她为爱情而神魂颠倒
She was head over heels in love
感觉自己就像 活在梦中一样
and felt like she was kinda living the dream.
到夏威夷还有世界各地 去旅游
Hawaii and traveling the world,
她觉得 这个感觉真的很棒
I think she really felt this was wonderful.
对着镜头 开怀大笑
Whee! Smile for the camera with your big tongue!
妈妈好棒
Nice Mommy!
有了孩子之后 她又活过来了
Having babies, she just came alive.
真是个漂亮男孩 真是个漂亮男孩
What a beautiful boy, what a beautiful boy!
她觉得 "天呐 这是真的"
I think that she felt, "Wow, this isC this is real.
"一切很有价值"
This is valuable.
"这让我感觉很重要"
This makes me important.
我觉得她是个很棒的妈妈 真的
I think she was a great mother, I really do.
如果她连我都能忍受得了
I mean, if she could put up with me, she was…
任何能忍受得了我的人 都是好妈妈
anyone who could put up with me was a good mom.
Madison 你不是个坏孩子
Maddie, you were not a bad child.
我不知道 你为什么这么想
I don’t know where you get that.
你喜欢吗 这个好吗
Do you like it? Is it good?
我一直知道 你以后会拍东西
I always knew you’d be doing this
因为你总是像个小导演
because you were always the little director.
真的很有意思
It was hysterical.
你就是镜头背后的男人
You were the man behind the camera.
好了
That’s it.
很奇怪吗
Isn’t that weird?
看看我的牙齿
It’s - Look at my teeth.
很高兴 看到你在做这些
I’m glad to see you’re doing it.
他们有了你和Ali
They had you and Ali.
所以一开始 生活是很美好的
And, um… so, I think in the beginning it was very good.
但是世事难料对吧 世事无常
But, you know, stuff happens, right? Things change.
这是关于Barbie被杀的纪录片
Is the documentary about Barbie being murdered,
还是关于Barbie是谁的
or is the documentary about
纪录片
who Barbie was?
关于她是谁
Who she was.
是吗
Yeah?
那只是一部分
It’s, it’s about, I mean, that’s a part,
这是关于她的人生的 那是她
it’s about her life, and that is a part
人生中的一部分 然后
of her life, and then that…
这部纪录片 也是关于整个家庭的
it’s also kind of about the family, too.
她来了
There she is.
白色内搭 紫色外套
Purple on white.
我不知道什么变了
I don’t know what had turned
但有些事情变了
but something had turned.
我记得有一次 我看着她
I remember looking at
她看起来 非常不同寻常
her one time and she looked so different,
她好像很伤心 但又假装没事
she seemed hurt, like she was pretending.
我能看出来 他们的感情 发生了变化
And I could tell that their relationship was different.
后来我们去她家 看她的时候
And then when we would visit,
Jeff都没在家里
Jeff wasn’t even there,
我们只是看到了 Barbie
it was just visiting Barbie.
我没有过问这件事
And I didn’t ask her about it,
I didn’t talk about it,
很后悔我没有这样做
and I’m sorry I didn’t.
她遇到你爸爸的时候
I mean, she hadC was living such a privileged life
过着如此优渥的生活
when she met your father,
你们也过着 如此优渥的生活
and you guys were living such a privileged life.
这是爸爸
There’s daddy.
他是个很棒的人 很勤奋工作的人
What a wonderful man, and a hard worker.
但是你爸爸
But your dad got in trouble,
在南方电气工作时 惹了麻烦
when he was working at Southern Electric, and
因为他在海外非法交易
they fired him for making
公司解雇了他
an illegal deal out of the country,
但他把他们 告上法庭
but he took them to court, and he
他应该是 以诽谤人格罪提起诉讼
won $3.5 million I believe,
赢得了350美元赔偿金
for defamation of character.
也为了纪念 爸爸在法庭上打赢官司
It’s also dedicated to daddy’s victory, in court.
经历过在南方电气这些事情后
I think after what happened at Southern,
他发生了变化
something changed him.
你妈妈总说 这对他打击很大
Your mom always said that that was such a blow to him.
他总是试着
He was always trying to
通过各种商业冒险 证明自己
prove himself by doing other ventures.
之后 当他开始旅行时
And then, when he started to travel,
他就不回家了 那时候问题开始出现
and not come home, that’s when the problems began
因为你妈妈 总是被孤零零丢在家里
because your mother was left alone all the time.
她感觉自己 就像个单亲妈妈
And she was feeling like a single mother,
她感觉自己
and, uh… she was feeling
好像被遗弃了
as though she had been deserted.
你爸爸 差不多就是抛弃了她
Your dad pretty much abandoned her,
所以她提起离婚诉讼
so she filed for divorce.
那对她来说
That was really a tough decision
是个很艰难的决定
for her to make, you know?
你爸爸迁怒于你妈妈
The anger that your father had  over your mother
导致婚姻破裂 主要是因为他没有在物质上支持她
ending the marriage came out in not supporting her, physically.
没有帮她 抚养孩子
Not giving child support,
没有支付账单 没有处理
not paying for the bills, not taking care
任何家庭经济问题
of any of the financial, uh,
有一部分开支 是他理应承担的
parts that he was supposed to take care of.
他只想 让她倾家荡产
He just wanted to impoverish her;
这好像 就是他设定的目标
it seemed like a goal that he had set for himself.
看到发生的这一切 真的很让人难过
And it was very sad to see that all happen,
因为他们还有 这么多
because there are so many more
美好的事情值得注意 而不是复仇和愤怒
wonderful things to focus on than revenge and anger.
再见 我爱你
Bye-bye! I love you.
再见 再见
Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
再见 爸爸
Bye-bye, daddy!
2010年 3月5日
谋杀案发生的两天后
晚上好 女士们先生们
Good evening ladies and gentlemen,
欢迎你们今晚的到来
welcome for coming tonight.
麦迪逊警察局
Madison Police Department―*
以及康涅狄格州警
with the Connecticut State Police and
以及来自纽黑文郡的
the office of the Chief State’s Attorney
州首席检察官办公室
from New Haven County―
还在继续调查 麦迪逊市中间海滩路西谋杀案中
we’re continuing our investigation into the death of
Barbara Hamburg的死因
Barbara Hamburg from Middle Beach Road West in Madison.
目前 我们正在努力
Um, at this time, we’re seeking to
查清死者前夫的下落
locate her former husband,
Jeffrey Hamburg 1948年8月5日出生
Jeffrey Hamburg, date of birth 8/5/48.
是一名白人男性 六英尺高
He’s a white male, six feet
高个子 淡褐色眼睛
tall, with hazel eyes.
谋杀案调查
麦迪逊
上一个已知住址 为康涅狄格州
Last known address is in West Hartford,
西哈特福德 Timberwood路
Connecticut, Timberwood Road.
警方从哈特福德 到西哈特福德
There’s a state-wide manhunt on
重磅新闻
犯罪现场线索
哈特福德新闻室
甚至在温莎市 开始搜查他的下落
from Hartford to West Hartford, even over to Windsor.
我们先从 西哈特福德开始
We started off in West Hartford.
我们来看一下 可以看到州警
Take a look, this is what we found: State Police at aC
重磅新闻
西哈特福德一名男子
疑似与麦迪逊谋杀案有关系
停在一栋 高级的公寓大楼面前
at an affluent condo complex
根据记录 屋主正是Jeffrey Hamburg
where the owner of record is Jeffrey Hamburg.
还有几名警探
There are also some detectives
正在Alstrom工程工厂附近
at an Alstrom Engineering plant
据说Hamburg就是在这里工作
where they say Hamburg worked.
他们在那 也找不到他
They could not find him there as well.
跟我们交谈的邻居说
Now, the neighbors we talked
Hamburg住在这栋公寓大楼
to say Hamburg lives in this condo complex,
他在这里 住了大概一年了
he’s lived in this unit here for about a year,
但是在一年时间里
though in that year-time,
他们只见过他一次
they’ve only seen him once.
在门前台阶上 他的报纸没有被动过
On his front doorstep, the newspapers sit unread,
这个地方的人 感到很惊讶
and the people in the area were surprised,
特别是当他们看到州警
especially when they saw the State Police come up
过来按前门铃 来找他的时候
and ring the front door, Looking for him.
你觉得 谁有可能
Do you have any opinion on who you…
干了这件事
you think could have done this?
在我看来 如果她活下来
Well, it seems to me that your father
你爸爸似乎是那个
was in the position to lose the most if she…
损失最大的人
if she lived.
那天他本来应该去坐牢的
And, um, that was the day he was supposed to go to jail.
Barbara Hamburg今天早上
Barbara Hamburg was to be in court
本来应该和她前夫Jeffrey Hamburg 打官司
this morning with her ex-husband, Jeffrey Hamburg,
但那天听证会 她再也没出现过
but she never showed up for that court hearing.
这对夫妻 2005年离婚了
The couple divorced in 2005,
之后很多年 存在法律纠纷
followed by years of legal wrangling,
他还欠孩子的抚养费
and he owed backCchild support.
他一直不给钱
I mean, he had been withholding money.
按照Barb对我说的 她要把他
From what Barb told me, she was going
送进监狱
to throw him in jail.
Richard Callahan
Richard Callahan,
是Barbara Hamburg的财产律师
attorney for Barbara Hamburg’s estate,
他说Jeff Hamburg 一直说自己破产了
says Jeff Hamburg has cried broke for too long
但同时又过着 骄奢淫逸的生活
while living a lavish lifestyle.
好吧 第一条
Alright, take-one.
开始
Marker.
Richard Callahan
我妈妈的律师
我把那天我告诉州警的话 告诉你
I’ll tell you what I told the State Police that day.
法院要求你爸爸
Your father had been ordered,
你爸爸也答应 给你们一些钱
and had promised to make certain payments.
你爸爸 要么带着钱来
Either your dad showed up with the money
不然我就会通知法庭
or I’d be asking the court to find him
他蔑视法庭命令
in contempt of the court’s orders
法院会把他关起来 直到他付钱为止
and incarcerate him until he, until he paid.
他一共欠多少钱
How much did he owe in total?
欠你妈妈 15万3千美元
$153,000 to your mother,
欠你和你妹妹 32万4千美元
and $324,000 to you and your sister.
毫无疑问
There was no question
他在3月3号 没拿出那笔钱
he did not have the money on March 3rd.
警方说Jeff Hamburg
Police say Jeff Hamburg was stealing money
和Barbara离婚之后 四年来
from his daughter’s college fund
一直从自己女儿的大学基金中偷钱
about four years after he and his wife Barbara divorced.
那天什么时候开庭
What time did court start that day?
9点半
9:30.
一般你妈妈会在9点 9点15赶到
Normally, your mom’s there at 9, 9:15.
我爸爸 是什么样的举止
What was my dad’s demeanor like?
我不知道这样说 合不合适
I don’t know whether I could say
他的举止 当时发生了一些变化
there was a change in his demeanor,
但是他和他的律师
but there was no complaint to me
都没有和我抱怨什么
from him or his lawyer saying,
没有问"你客户在哪 为什么还没来"
"Where is your client, why isn’t she here?"
这很让我惊讶
And that is what struck me.
但我的话要说周全
But I should back up, because…
因为这好像在暗示 我知道你爸爸
that suggests that I-I know that your father…
做了什么 但是我并不知道
did something, which I do not know.
他只是因为那天的情况
He just was the prime suspect
被定性为头号嫌疑犯
because of the circumstances of that day.
所有父母都有梦想
All parents have dreams,
他们很明确
and they have definite ideas of
想让你成为什么样的人
what they want you to be.
一位永不满足的父亲 让生活艰难
It isn’t easy with a father who is never satisfied,
他总是想让你 与众不同
always wants you a little different,
更出众一点 更符合他的期望
and a little better, more like his dream.
我遇到你的时候
From the time that I met you,
我 *你和你爸爸的关系并不好
the relationship with your dad, um, was not good.
Erin Corbett
我的高中心理辅导老师
他很有控制欲
You know, it was very… controlling.
生日快乐
我觉得 你和你妈妈很亲
I think you had a really close relationship with your mom,
可能比大多数少年和妈妈的关系都好
probably closer than most teenage boys.
在某些方面 你和同龄人一样
You were more like peers in some ways,
所以她给你立规矩时
so you had a hard time
你感觉自己很难受
when she tried to lay down the law with you.
你在嗑药
You were using substances and
然后被学校开除
you were expelled from school.
你爸爸因为我写的一封信 大发雷霆
Your dad got angry about a letter I had written
我在写给法庭的信中 写道
to the court that stated that
你不想在他的房子里生活 不想去他家
you didn’t want to liveC go to his house.
也不想 和他待在一起
Or be, spend time with him.
他觉得 那是我的一面之词
He thought that that was my opinion.
我们澄清了事实
So, once we clarified really that
我其实 复述的是你的原话
I was stating something that you had stated,
解释清楚了
it was cleared up.
但我收到了 他的律师发来的传票
But I got a- a subpoena from a lawy-from his lawyer.
对 我记得
Yeah, I remember it.
他吓坏了
He, like, freaked out.
他开始
He, like, started like
攻击你
attacking you, kinda.
然后你妈妈 第二天打来
And then your mom called me the next day,
告诉我 你很担心我
to tell me that you were worried
你不喜欢你爸爸
about me, that you didn’t like
这样对待我
the way your dad was treating me.
你能说一下 谋杀案
Can you talk about afterC
发生后几个月 是什么样的吗
like, months after the murder?
你来找我
You came to see me.
你离开了学校 但你回来找我
You left school and you came back to see me.
不过只接受了几个疗程的治疗
Only for a few sessions though.
因为你当时的状态
Because, you know, you were not in a place
没办法正常上学
that you could function in school.
你有点担心 自己的安全
You were afraid of like, your own safety.
之后不久 你就中断了
And then, shortly after all communication with
和你父亲的 所有联系
your dad stopped.
我知道 你爸爸有些过去
I knew that there were things in your dad’s history.
嗨 够了
Hi! Enough!
你妈妈和我说过
Your mom told me that he had been
他参与过国外的一些事情
involved in something overseas.
我不知道他有多少护照 五个吗
He had, I don’t know how many passports, five?
我们很惊讶
So, it was a surprise for us.
从南方电气的总裁
To go from the CEO of Southern Electric
变成了鲜少有人了解的人
to a life that few people could begin to understand....
电气能源
electric energy...
去找爸爸
get Daddy.
爸爸在哪里 爸爸在哪里
Where’s daddy? Where’s daddy?
2010年 3月17日
谋杀案发生之后的两周
第一次看到了Jeffrey Hamburg
A first look at Jeffrey Hamburg
他今早和律师一起 前往法庭
as he walks to court this morning with his lawyer.
这是他第一次 公开亮相
This is his first public appearance,
出现在 赡养费和子女抚养费听证会上
at an alimony and child support hearing,
此前其前妻Barbara Beach Hamburg
since his ex-wife, Barbara Beach Hamburg,
在本月早些时候 被人谋杀
was found murdered earlier this month.
这位前夫 聘请了知名
The ex-husband has hired well-known
刑事辩护律师 Hugh Keefe
criminal defense lawyer Hugh Keefe.
Lynch Traub Keefe & Errante事务所
Lynch, Traub, Keefe & Errante
处理各种刑事案件
handles all kinds of criminal cases:
Hugh.F.Keefe*
管理合伙人
谋杀 性骚扰 绑架
murder, sexual assault, kidnapping,
挪用公款 偷税漏税 密谋
embezzlement, tax evasion, conspiracies.
你爸爸立刻聘请了 一名律师
Your father immediately got an attorney
这样他就 不用被警方带走了
so that he wouldn’t have to go to the police.
如果我有所隐瞒的话
If I thought I had something to hide,
我肯定不想 和警方谈话
I wouldn’t be wanting to talk to the police.
今天出庭的还有 警察
Also in court today: police.
这是一个例行的 多方听证会
This is a routine, ah, support hearing.
今天法庭里的警察
There are more police officers than
比律师还多
lawyers in that courtroom today.
警察遇到这样的情况时
The police, when they have a situation like this,
会自然而然地 想到配偶或者前任
automatically look at the spouse or ex-spouse.
你爸爸 聘请的律师
The attorney that your dad hired,
在法庭里 让人们感到害怕
people were afraid of him in the courtroom.
他控制力很强
He was pretty masterful.
Keefe说Hamburg上周 给了警方
Keefe says Hamburg gave police
一份他的 DNA和毛发样本
a sample of his DNA and hair last week.
肯定是所有检测结果都不匹配
I assume everything came back negative
否则他早就被逮捕了
or he would have been arrested.
出席今天离婚后听证会的还有
Also at today’s postCdivorce hearing:
Barbara的姐姐 Conway Beach
Barbara’s sister, Conway Beach.
你和Jeffrey聊过了吗
Have you spoken to Jeffrey at all?
没有 我只知道这么多
No, I have not, and that’s all I have.
你的外甥和外甥女 还好吗
How’s your niece and nephew?
你觉得 警方为什么没有
Why do you think the police haven’t
就我父亲的情况立案
opened a case against my father about the murder?
我觉得警察
I think the police were...
在处理你母亲的谋杀案时 失误了
dropped the ball on your mother’s murder,
这就是事实
if you want the truth.
很难想象 在麦迪逊这样的小城
I mean, it’s very difficult to think of a small town,  like Madison,
警方无法破解这一惊人的罪行
not being able to solve this egregious crime.
感觉警察好像是 搞砸了
It sounds like there was a sort of screw-up
或者是DNA出了问题 我不太清楚
or something with the DNA, I’m not really sure.
警察母亲
有谋杀嫌疑
谋杀发生日
2010年3月3日
康涅狄格开了一所新的 尸检实验室
2010年4月23日
他们让我们家人 等DNA检测结果
We were asked, as a family, to wait to run the DNA
因为新建了 一所DNA实验室
because apparently there was a new DNA lab being built,
那个实验室会是最棒的
and it was gonna be the best.
康涅狄格尸检实验室
下午好 女士们先生们
Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen,
很高兴来到梅里登
it is a pleasure to be here in Meriden
庆祝州尸检实验室
to celebrate the groundbreaking
动土开工仪式
for the State Forensic Science Laboratory.
众所周知 康涅狄格州
Connecticut is a known leader
在尸检领域 是著名领先者
in the field of forensic science,
这个项目 将强化这样的优势
and this project will reinforce this distinction.
所以我们等着新DNA实验室建成
So we waited for this new DNA lab to be built.
我们相信 它是全美国
We believe we are the premier laboratory
乃至全世界 最先进的实验室
in the United States and in the world...
他们做了DNA检测 但试剂盒出了问题
They ran the DNA, and, um, the DNA kit was faulty.
DNA证据提取需要数月
对方有罪或者无罪
...And the difference between verdicts of guilty
很大程度上取决于
and verdicts of not guilty depends to a great extent
我们这样的实验室能否公正无私
upon the integrity of a laboratory such as ours.
现在州犯罪实验室
Now the state crime lab is under
现在被施加了 额外的压力
some extra pressure right now
因为最近 对DNA检测过程的审查
because a recent audit of its DNA processes
发现了一些问题
came up with some problems
它的认证资质也过期了
and its accreditation also has expired.
说实话 madison
To be quite honest with you, Madison,
我都不知道 有没有DNA保存下来
I don’t even know if there is any DNA left.
这真是把我吓坏了
And it scares the shit out of me.
尸检结束后 她就被火化了
After the medical examiner finished, she was cremated.
这是家族传统
I mean, that’s a family tradition.
早知道是这样
Knowing what I know now,
我应该再多等一阵子
one should wait a little longer
直到所有证据 在尸体火化前
until all evidence has been collected properly,
都收集完毕
before you cremate them,
因为现在DNA很重要了
because DNA is so important now.
你还好吗
You alright?
抱歉 姥姥
I’m sorry Grammy.
没事
Yeah.
有人漏掉了什么东西
Somebody’s missing something.
不用DNA也能破案的
Cases can be solved without DNA.
谋杀案发生当日
2010年3月3日
麦迪逊警察局
There’s been some scuttlebutt about
出了一些流言蜚语 不怎么光彩
the Madison Police Department being less than ethical,
我觉得 需要调查一下
that, um, I think needs to be investigated.
六名警察被辞退 警长被迫停职
2006-2009
你也知道 州检察官
As you know, the State’s Attorney
现在正在调查 麦迪逊警察局
now investigating the ongoings here
出现的各种事情
at the Madison Police Department.
他们没有抓捕犯人
Instead of making arrests,
两名警察反而被 逮了起来
two Madison police officers are placed under arrest.
三名警察被开除
Three police officers have been fired.
警察被控
Officers were allegedly meeting with
招妓 光顾脱衣舞会
prostitutes, frequenting strip clubs
按摩院 还成立了摩托车帮派
and massage parlors, and establishing a motorcycle gang.
咖啡店里 人们常谈的就是坏警察
Conversation at the coffee shop is often about bad cops.
人们有点厌倦了 警察局里
People here are tired of the little bit of corruption
日渐猖獗的腐败问题
that keeps cropping up in the police department.
一名麦迪逊警官被剥夺了警徽
A Madison police officer is stripped of his badge.
因为滥用警局数据 被停职逮捕
...Suspended and arrested for abusing police data,
被指控从餐厅偷海鲜
charged with stealing seafood from a restaurant,
现在被控从镇上的加油站偷汽油
now accused of stealing gasoline from the town pump.
真是个问题 你需要信任的人
It's a concern when the people you trust to,
需要托付要事的人
um, to take care of things are less
自己本来就不诚实
than honest themselves.
我没有证据 但是很担心
I have no proof of that, only a lot of concern.
这是你长大的地方
This is the town you will grow up in.
一个温暖美好的世界
A nice warm world.
快乐安全的社区
A happy secure community.
你在这种氛围中成长
An atmosphere that prepares you
找到自己在世界上的归宿
to find your place in the world with confidence
充满自信 发挥自己的才能
and the best use of your ability.
你好
Hello?
嘿 我是麦迪逊
Hey, it’s Madison.
嘿 怎么了
Hey, what’s going on?
通话中
警探Neal Mulhern
我之前和你说过
I told you before, I’m doing a documentary
我在拍一部 有关妈妈的纪录片
on my mother for a class...
对
Yeah.
我在想
Um, and I was just seeing, um,
有什么办法可以进行采访
if there is any way I could get an interview with someone,
就是用一些
just about... just to go over like what the...
犯罪现场的内容 可以放在纪录片里
crime scene or something that I can use for my documentary.
我得先和领导商量下
Um, I'l have to check with the chief,
也许他会愿意 这我不清楚
maybe he'd be willing to, it's beyond me, you know...
-好的  -他说了算 但是
-Okay. -He's the boss of bosses, but, I mean,
你知道我们不能说得太细
you know we really can't get into much detail, you know?
-对  -我是说 问题是案件还在审理
-Right. -I mean, the problem is it's open.
如果我们开始公布任何细节
If we start releasing any details,
毕竟案子还在审理中
you know, it's an active case
所以我们不能泄露出去
so we can't just give stuff out
因为这可能会给我们造成困扰
because it could come back to haunt us.
我们刚刚又对整个案件做了全面梳理
We just did another comprehensive review of the entire case again, um,
-我们还要再跟很多人面谈  -好的
-we're going to be going back and interviewing a lot of people. -Okay.
你知道我们也有一些问题
And, uh, you know we have some questions
想问你
that have popped up for you, too.
好 你周五早上
Alright, um, Is there any way you could
能过来见我吗
come in and meet with me Friday morning?
是的 当然
Yeah, yeah. Absolutely.
好的
Okay.
他不知道我们能否接受采访 但是
He doesn't know if we can do an interview, but like, what if...
我周五要接受审问
I...I'm going in for questioning on Friday.
我带录音机怎么样
What if I, like, brought in  a recorder?
这很冒险
Risky.
制片人的声音
或者我可以用手机录下来
Or I could record it with my phone.
很冒险的
Risky.
这是值得的
It'd be worth it.
是的 看看他们在问你什么问题吧
Yeah, it would. See what kind of questions they're asking you.
距麦迪逊一英里
麦迪逊镇学校
麦迪逊警察局
Madison 今天我们怎么来警局了
Madison, what brings us to the police station today?
我要接受审问
I am, uh, about to get interrogated,
这算是我所忍受的众多事情之一
it's just one of the many things that I have to put up with,
自从有人杀害了我母亲
since someone came and killed my mother.
你好 需要帮忙吗
Hi, can I help you?
嘿 我来找Mulhern警探
Hey, uh, I'm here to see Detective Mulhern.
你叫什么
Your name, please?
Madison
Uh, Madison.
Madison吗
Madison?
是的
Yeah.
这是你的姓还是你的名
Is that your last name or your first name?
我的名
Uh, that's my first name.
你姓什么
And your last name?
Hamburg
Hamburg.
好 我会转达你找他
Okay, I'l tell them that you are here.
好的 谢谢你
Okay, thank you.
我都不知道自己有没有准备好
I don't even know if I'm, like, prepared for this.
请坐
Have a seat.
你最近在忙什么
What you been up to?
Christopher Sudock警探
Neal Mulhern警探
没忙什么 就是学校的事
Um, not much, just like, school and stuff.
还在佐治亚州吗*
Still down in Georgia?
是的
Yeah.
今天有什么事吗
So, what's up today?
你来找我们什么事吗
What're you looking for from us?
我们只是想看看 能不能给一个采访的机会
Um, we're just seeing if there's any way we can get an interview?
现在还不行
Yeah, we're not, that's, you know,
案子还没结 不能接受采访
with an open case they'l never let that happen.
还没到那一步
We're not there yet.
这案子很棘手 确实很棘手
It's just a tough case. Tough case.
你还记得你那天做了什么吗
Do you remember any more about what you did that day, or...?
我去了Chick-Fil-A快餐店*
I went to ChickCFilCA.
那天我没去上课 至少别人是这么告诉我的
I didn't go to class that day. Or so I'm told.
你记得那天有没有去便利店
Did you remember going to any convenience stores that day?
买烟
Cigarettes?
我当时在抽烟
I was still smoking.
肯定他们已经告诉你DNA的事了
I'm sure they've told you some of the DNA stuff.
现场有一根香烟
Well, there's a cigarette there.
跟你父亲的DNA不匹配
Doesn't come back to your father.
跟我的匹配
Goes back to me?
是的
Yeah.
在你母亲的指甲里有DNA
There's DNA under your mother's fingernails.
我的吗
Of me?
Hamburg家族男性的
Male Hamburg lineage.
就你所知 你觉得是谁干的
With everything you know, who do you think did this?
我不知道
I have no idea.
我们不能排除你父亲的可能
We can't eliminate your father.
不能排除
We can't.
排除他的唯一办法是 他接受审讯
The only way we can eliminate him is him talking to us,
提供他那天的行踪
providing his whereabouts for that day.
我们需要些证据 来排除他的嫌疑
Something we can verify to put him out of the picture.
话虽如此 这并不能彻底排除他的嫌疑
With that said, that doesn't even eliminate him from involvement.
你比任何人都了解你父亲
You know your father better than anybody.
他会干出这种事吗
Is he capable of something like this?
我从没见过他对任何人有暴力行为
I've never seen him be violent towards anyone.
控制欲强吗
Controlling?
很强
He's very controlling.
还好指使人且自私自利
And manipulative. And selfish.
你父亲欠你母亲一大笔钱
Your father owed your mother a huge amount of money.
是的 几十万吧
Yeah, hundreds of thousands of dollars.
他的钱都干嘛用了
Where did all his money go?
这是我想知道的一个大问题
That's a big question I want to know.
你觉得你爸爸有海外银行账户吗
Do you think your dad has offshore bank accounts?
我不知道
I have no idea.
麦迪逊警察局
他在海外做什么 对我一直是保密的
It's...what he does overseas has always been a secret to me.
我觉得目前最重要的问题是 过来 坐下来
The big problem I have is, come in and sit down,
洗清罪名
and clear your name.
我不能 我和他联系不多 知道的不多
I can't...I just...I don't have enough contact with him to know.
你和他没有联系了吗
You don't have contact with him anymore?
联系过 我跟他聊过 但是
No, I talk to him, but like,
心底里很难问他这样的问题
emotionally it's pretty hard to ask him questions like that.
你跟他说纪录片的事了吗
Have you told him about the documentary?
说了 最近 因为我想采访他
Yeah, recently, because I wanted to interview him.
他怎么说的
What did he say about that?
他说 他真的很想帮我
He said, he really wants to help me
但他不知道自己能做什么
but he just doesn't know what he can do.
我猜是他律师说他不能去
I guess it's his lawyer, like, saying he can't.
是的 我让他跟他律师谈过很多次
Yeah, I've had him talk to his lawyer, like,
也说了他可以和律师一起接受采访
many times, told I'l do an interview with his lawyer in the room,like,
我还在想办法采访他
I... I'm still working on getting an interview with him.
当你在拍纪录片时
When you're doing your documentary is it on video,
你是录音吗
or is it a...Are you recording it?
会拍摄视频
It's a video.
你愿意把视频交给我们看吗
Is that something you'd be willing to turn over to us to look at?
你知道 有时候人们会犹豫要不要跟警察聊
You know, sometimes people are hesitant to talk to the police,
但他们很愿意告诉你一些
but they're more than willing to tell you something,
我们不知道的事
uh, that we don't know.
你爸爸 他有没有直接告诉你
Your dad, has he ever point blank told you
"我跟这事一点关系都没有"
"I had nothing to do with this?"
我从来没有问过他
I've never, like, asked him.
我想问他呢
I want to ask him.
我觉得这部纪录片是我唯一的机会 可以那样问他
This documentary is the only chance I feel like I can.
如果我问他 我想当面问
If I ask him that, I want to do it in person.
我害怕那样问他
And it...it scares me to do that.
如果有任何可能是他干的
If there's any possibility that he's capable of doing that,
这会让我很害怕
it just scares the shit out of me.
进展如何
So how'd it go?
还好吧 他们什么都不想提供给我们
Uh, good. I mean, they don't want to give us anything,
但他们想要纪录片
but they want the doc.
-他们想要我们的纪录片  -你有没有告诉他们
-They want like all of our files. -Did you tell them...
这对他们有什么帮助
What would it, what would it help them?
他们认为
They think that, like,
人们会在采访中 告诉我们一些不会对他们说的事
people would tell us things in interviews that they wouldn't tell them.
嘿
?Hey!
-嘿  -有什么事吗
-Hey. -What's...what's going on?
没什么 我只是想跟你聊聊天
Nothing, I'm just trying to catch up with you.
与爸爸通话
好 我想问你
Yeah, um, I wanted to ask if you,
又和你律师谈了吗
uh, talked to your attorney again?
我不能接受采访
Yeah, I can't. I can't.
我不能接受采访 很抱歉
There's no way. Sorry about that.
你不能接受采访的主要原因是什么
Uh, what's like, the main reason you can't?
Madison 我不能跟你说
Madison, I just can't discuss it.
这事不能聊 所以
It's just... it's a... an unqualified no, so...
那我能问你几个问题吗
Then can I ask you some questions?
不能 Madison 就这样吧
No. Madison, just leave it at that.
我只想知道为什么
I just wanna know why,
为什么 我不能
why that...I can't...you...
为什么你都不跟我聊这事
why you can't even just talk to me.
我知道你想知道答案
I know you wanna know answers,
你也想知道你妈妈的事
and I know you wanna know about your mom,
还有她的有些事 但这不是
and her life and all that stuff but it's just-it's not...
也许几年以后 我们可以谈这个
maybe in years ahead, maybe we can have this conversation,
但现在不行
but not now.
我只是觉得这不公平
I just don't think that's fair.
是的 很多事情都不公平
Yeah. A lot of things are unfair.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我没感觉你很抱歉
I don't think that you're sorry.
好吧 信不信由你
Okay. Well, you can...you can believe me or not believe me.
这是你的选择
It's your choice.
你想这案子破案吗
Do you, do you want this case to get solved?
Madison 我不想再回答你的问题了
Madison, I'm not going to answer any more questions about it.
-就我而言  -就现在这个时候
-As far as... as far as I'm concerned ... -At this point...At this point
我不能再回答了 Madison 我不能再回答你的问题了
I cannot answer any more...Madison, I can't answer any more questions.
此时 说实话
At this point, I honestly, in my honest opinion,
不知道你想不想破案
don't know if you want this case to be solved.
我不知道比起破案
If...I don't know if you care more
你是否更想掩护自己
about covering yourself than this case being solved,
这没道理啊 因为这
which doesn't make any sense, because this, this,
如果这案子破了 你是无辜的
if this case is solved, and if you're innocent...
我没什么可说的 没什么可说的
I have nothing to add. I have nothing to add.
我对你母亲的生活一无所知 真的
I have no knowledge of your mother's life, uh, really.
你和她结婚13年了
You, you were married to her for 13 years,
你要面对
and you, you were dealing with
对 但是我一无所知
Yeah but I have no... I don't know anything.
你要我怎么相信你
How...how...how do you expect me to trust you?
Madison 这是你必须做的决定
Madison, that's a decision you have to make.
是吗 这打算对此保密
Is it? It's a decision based on your secrecy.
Madison 你必须做出个决定
Madison, it's a decision, it's a decision that you have to make.
我希望你能理解
I would hope that you would understand,
但如果你不想做决定就算了
but if you don't, you don't.
这决定由你来做
I mean, that's your decision.
也许有一天 你会鼓起勇气
Maybe one day, you'l get the courage together to,
去面对这事且去改变一些事情
to face this stuff and change something but,
但在那之前 你什么都不会说的
until then, that's...you're gonna stay in the same spot.
你现在成了阻止破案的主要因素之一
Because that's...you are one of the main pieces that's stopping everything.
我今天还有别的事 我先挂了
I guess I gotta... I have other things I gotta do today.
好吧
Okay.
好
Alright.
拜
Bye.
我们试过了
We tried, I mean...
他不想帮忙
doesn't wanna... doesn't want to help,
还是没有什么进展
doesn't want anything to change.
?这里是我发现妹妹被杀的地方
This is where I found my sister murdered.
你儿子也在这里 Barbie
He's here Barbie.
我要说的就是我爱你
I guess all I want to say is I love you,